Fortune favors the bold.
Uncharted is a action, adventure film directed by Ruben Fleischer.
A young street-smart, Nathan Drake and his wisecracking partner Victor “Sully” Sullivan embark on a dangerous pursuit of
“the greatest treasure never found” while also tracking clues that may lead to Nathan’s long-lost brother.
Nathan Drake, played by Tom Holland.
Victor 'Sully' Sullivan, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Chloe Frazer, played by Sophia Ali.
Jo Braddock, played by Tati Gabrielle.
Santiago Moncada, played by Antonio Banderas.
The Scotsman, played by Steven Waddington.
Uncharted is a 2022 American action adventure film based on the video game franchise
developed by Naughty Dog and published by Sony Interactive Entertainment.
Directed by Ruben Fleischer from a screenplay by Rafe Lee Judkins, Art Marcum, and Matt Holloway, it stars Tom Holland as Nathan Drake and Mark Wahlberg
as Victor Sullivan, with Sophia Ali, Tati Gabrielle (in her debut film appearance), and Antonio Banderas starring in supporting roles.
In the film, Drake is recruited by Sullivan in a race against corrupt billionaire Santiago Moncada (Banderas) and
mercenary leader Jo Braddock (Gabrielle) to locate the fabled treasure of the Magellan expedition.
The film entered development in 2008, with producer Avi Arad stating that he would be working
with Sony Pictures to develop a film adaptation of the video game franchise.
It was then in development hell with various directors,
screenwriters, and lead cast members attached at various points.
Filmmakers David O.
Russell, Neil Burger, Seth Gordon, Dan Trachtenberg, Shawn Levy, and Travis Knight were
initially signed to direct, while Wahlberg was set to play Drake in early development.
Holland was cast as Drake in May 2017, and Fleischer
was hired as director in early 2020.
Filming began in March 2020, but was halted by the COVID-19 pandemic.
It resumed in July and finished in October, with locations
including Boston, Barcelona, New York City, and Kiamba.
Originally set to be released on December 18, 2020, the film
faced major delays due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
It eventually premiered at the Coliseum in Barcelona on February 7, 2022, and was released in the
United States on February 18 by Columbia Pictures (via Sony Pictures Releasing).
The film received mixed reviews from critics, but was a commercial success, grossing $407.1 million worldwide against
a $120 million budget, making it the fourth-highest-grossing video game film at the time of release.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of lighter, treasure hunt,
treasure map, based on video game, lost treasure.